DONGJAE LEE

dongjael@mit.edu • dongjaelee1.github.io • github.com/dongjaelee1

SUMMARY

I am currently a PhD student at MIT PDOS. My research interests include verification of computer systems, concurrency, and security. I have research experience with the Coq proof assistant, compiler verification, concurrent program verification, and security.

EDUCATION

Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering

Current

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, USA

M.S., Computer Science and Engineering

02.2024

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

- · Advised by Chung-Kil Hur
- Thesis: Operational Semantics for Expressing and Reasoning about Fairness Properties

B.S., Physics, Computer Science and Engineering (Double Major)

08.2021

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

EXPERIENCE

Software Foundations Lab, Seoul National University

03.2024 - 08.2024

Research Assistant: Seoul, South Korea

Max Planck Institute for Security and Privacy

03.2023 - 08.2023

Research Intern: Bochum, Germany

- Advised by Cătălin Hriţcu
- · Worked on secure compilation

Software Foundations Lab, Seoul National University

09.2020 - 08.2021

Research Intern: Seoul, South Korea

- Advised by Chung-Kil Hur
- · Worked on Conditional Contextual Refinement

ROK Army (Mandatory Military Service)

01.2019 - 08.2020

Sergeant: South Korea

Integrated Quantum Systems Lab, Seoul National University

04.2017 - 08.2017

Research Intern: Seoul, South Korea

- Advised by Dohun Kim
- Worked on NV center qubits, programming and developing devices for experiments

PUBLICATIONS

Refinement Composition Logic

Youngju Song, Dongjea Lee.

International Conference on Functional Programming (ICFP 2024)

SECOMP: Formally Secure Compilation of Compartmentalized C Programs

Jérémy Thibault, Roberto Blanco, **Dongjae Lee**, Sven Argo, Arthur Azevedo de Amorim, Aïna Linn Georges, Cătălin Hriţcu, Andrew Tolmach.

Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2024)

Stuttering for Free

Minki Cho*, Youngju Song*, **Dongjea Lee**, Lennard Gäher, Derek Dreyer.

International Conference on Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages, and Applications (OOPSLA 2023)

^{*}equal contribution

Fair Operational Semantics

Dongjae Lee*, Minki Cho*, Jinwoo Kim, Soonwon Moon, Youngju Song, Chung-Kil Hur.

Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI 2023)

Conditional Contextual Refinement

Youngju Song, Minki Cho, Dongjae Lee, Chung-Kil Hur, Michael Sammler, Derek Dreyer.

Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages (POPL 2023)

Sequential Reasoning for Optimizing Compilers under Weak Memory Concurrency

Minki Cho*, Sung-Hwan Lee*, **Dongjae Lee**, Chung-Kil Hur, Ori Lahav.

Conference on Programming Language Design and Implementation (PLDI 2022)

HONORS AND AWARDS

Master's Thesis Award 02.2024

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Seoul National University: Seoul, South Korea

TALKS

Fair Operational Semantics 06.2023

PLDI 2023: Orlando, Florida, United States

Overview of Fair Operational Semantics (as a part of introducing Software Foundations Lab) 02.2023

SIGPL Winter School 2023 (The Korean Institute of Information Scientists and Engineers): Seoul, South Korea

TEACHING

(TA) Topics in Programming Languages (Logic in computer science) 09.2023 - 12.2023

by Makoto Tatsuta: Seoul National University, Graduate level course

(TA) Principles of Programming 09.2022 - 12.2022

by Chung-Kil Hur: Seoul National University, Undergraduate level course

(TA) Principles and Practices of Software Development 03.2022 - 06.2022

by Chung-Kil Hur: Seoul National University, Undergraduate level course

ACTIVITIES

Developing a Cog tutorial for refinement-based verification: https://github.com/dongjaelee1/refinement-tutorial